Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/sidharthasinha-4b16964 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Global Delivery
Software Project Management
SDLC

Languages

English (Full Professional) Hindi (Native or Bilingual)

Honors-Awards

Best-In-Class Manager from MFG ADM Unit 2014

Pinnacle award for Delivery Excellence

Prima award (Silver) for Technology Excellence

PRIMA Award (Silver) for ensuring effective customer management, delivery excellence

Prima award (Silver) for Knowledge Management Initiatives

Sidhartha Sinha

Vice President at JP Morgan Chase & Co. Hyderabad

Summary

Strategic Program Management Leader with over 23 years of experience and track record of successfully managing P&L, operations and high performing teams

Strong experience in Product Management, IT Delivery, Program Management. Technical Project

Management, Portfolio Ownership, Sales and Consultancy. Built and managed large teams for delivery spanning multiple time zones. Key contributor for Account Strategy, Business Plans and Business Growth. Involved in various strategic multimillion \$ deals for Infosys. Responsible for organizational initiatives.

Areas of Expertise includes: Business Acquisition, Partner Management, P & L/ Operations Governance, Due Diligence & Portfolio analysis, Transition Management, Program & Project Management, Team building & leadership

Experience

JP Morgan Chase Vice President July 2016 - Present (4 years 2 months) Hyderabad Area, India

Infosys

12 years 7 months

Delivery Manager October 2015 - July 2016 (10 months)

Hyderābād Area, India

Managed a global team of 600 resources across various portfolios including Sales and Marketing, Partner Relationship Management, Enterprise Services, Channel Incentives.

Managing a diverse portfolio in ISV sector with P/L accountability, Portfolio size is 45 M USD

Group Project Manager

March 2011 - September 2015 (4 years 7 months)

Responsible for program & delivery management for multiple programs for a leading Hi Tech client (over \$ 45 million) including Program Management, Analysis, Solution delivery, Development, Deployment & Support across Hyderabad, Chennai, Pune & China.

Senior Project Manager

January 2008 - March 2011 (3 years 3 months)

Hyderabad Area, India

Led Multiple Programs in Partner IT (RXD IT)

o ALES (Partner IT Sustenance engagement) - Transitioned Partner platform from incumbent vendor. Led the prioritization process across clusters. Implemented several engineering excellence initiatives across portfolio. Led the team in delivering multiple successful releases across apps – PMC, Portal, PLX, Partner Dashboard, PDD & CVP

o Starting 2010 led Feature development work in Partner IT. Successfully implemented Distributed Scrum. Infy award for Knowledge Management initiative

Led Programs in Foundation Services

o Led delivery of SXP (Social eXperience Platform). The platform enables social media capabilities across MS.com

o Led effort for revamping MSVideo platform

Managed Presales for large Hitech Clients - Worked on multiple large consolidation deals (RXD, MBS, BIE, CFE IT) and several large proposals across multiple IT groups.

Senior Project Manager (Onsite BI lead)

July 2005 - December 2007 (2 years 6 months)

Redmond USA

Managed Infosys relation with Microsoft BI COE group. Onsite coordinator for Infosys programs in Corporate Strategy, Planning & Analysis IT - Rhythm Of Business Scorecarding program, Rev Plan, Targets, BWB apps. Worked as Analyst & Senior Program Manager in RoB Scorecarding program, leading coordination work with multiple groups at Microsoft

Project Manager January 2004 - June 2005 (1 year 6 months)

Managed delivery of several BI programs like Rhythm of Business, Revenue Planning, and Targets tool. Responsible for gathering & analysing business requirements, creating functional specifications and high level design (HLD) and acquiring sign-off. Involved in scope & time management and ensuring timely project delivery

Rapidigm Ltd
Project Manager
June 2003 - December 2003 (7 months)
Noida Area, India

Project Manager for Req Track 3.0 Tool. Interacted with multiple offices of Rapidigm Inc for requirement gathering, scope management, onsite-offshore coordination, resource allocation and team management. Requests for proposals (RFPs)

Intiqua Ltd (Earlier Netacross Ltd)
Project lead
May 1998 - April 2003 (5 years)

Successfully delivered several projects for multiple clients including Broadcom, Sun Microsystems, P&G, Outlook India Private Ltd, Netpilgrim, Microsoft India, Bennet Coleman & Company Private Ltd. As Project lead responsible for design, code reviews, requirements gathering. Led several projects at onshore for P&G and Broadcom. At offshore, led programs for Sun Microsystems, Outlook.money,MS India, Netpilgrim

Birlasoft Senior Software Engineer

July 1996 - May 1998 (1 year 11 months)

Noida

Involved in Software development. Part of the Internet team (MS Technology stack)

Education

Dayalbagh Educational Institute

Bachelor of Engineering, Electrical Engineering (1992 - 1996)

St. Peter's College Agra

ISC · (1990 - 1992)

Atomic Energy Central School AISSE · (1984 - 1990)